<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://aveniracademia.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://aveniracademia.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-23T19:33:44+08:00</updated><id>https://aveniracademia.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Avenir Academia</title><subtitle>An attempt to bring free software to the masses. See the about page for more information.</subtitle><author><name>Andrew Yu, et. al.</name></author><entry><title type="html">Fwd: Pumpkin Markets and One Bad Apple</title><link href="https://aveniracademia.org/2021/10/21/pumpkin-markets-and-one-bad-apple.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fwd: Pumpkin Markets and One Bad Apple" /><published>2021-10-21T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-10-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://aveniracademia.org/2021/10/21/pumpkin-markets-and-one-bad-apple</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aveniracademia.org/2021/10/21/pumpkin-markets-and-one-bad-apple.html">&lt;p&gt;This message is fowarded from the Free Software Foundation’s
“Free Software Supporter” mailing list. The original message is
as below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Free Software Supporter,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine your local farmers market: every Saturday the whole town
comes together to purchase fresh and homemade goods, enjoy the
entertainment, and find that there is always something for
everyone. Whatever you need, you can find it here, and anyone can
sign up to have their own little stand. It is a wonderful place,
or so it seems. Now, imagine starting out as a pumpkin farmer,
and you want to sell your pumpkins at this market. The market
owner asks 30% of every pumpkin that you sell. It’s steep, but
the market owner – we’ll call him &lt;em&gt;Mr. Apple&lt;/em&gt; – owns all the
markets in your area, so you have little choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s continue this analogy and imagine that, since it is a
little hard for you to make ends meet, you decide to tell your
customers that they can come visit you at your farm to purchase
pumpkins. &lt;em&gt;Mr. Apple&lt;/em&gt; overhears and shuts your stand down. You
explain that your business cannot be profitable this way, but the
grumpy market owner says that you can either comply or find
another place. At the end of your rope, you look for information
about starting your own farmers market, but it seems &lt;em&gt;Mr. Apple&lt;/em&gt;
owns every building in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of Apple announcing its new products, attention is
drawn away from its ongoing battle to maintain its subjugation
over users globally.  The Netherlands’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theglobeandmail.com/business/international-business/european-business/article-dutch-watchdog-finds-apples-app-store-payment-rules-are-anti/&quot;&gt;Authority for Consumers
and Markets (ACM)&lt;/a&gt; last month informed the U.S. technology
giant of its decision that the rules around the in-app payment
system are anticompetitive, making it the first antitrust
regulator to conclude that the company has abused market power in
the App Store. And while Apple is appealing this verdict, the
European Union is charging the company with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/apple-to-face-eu-antitrust-charge-over-nfc-chip/article36871254.ece&quot;&gt;another antitrust
claim&lt;/a&gt; concerning the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globally, about 17% of all mobile phone users have an iPhone, but
Apple products and the iOS operating system are more popular in
the West, which has a substantial effect on those numbers. To
illustrate, in March 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/236550/percentage-of-us-population-that-own-a-iphone-smartphone/&quot;&gt;47% of all smartphone users&lt;/a&gt; in
the United States were iPhone users. Apple holds 56.7% of the
United States mobile operating system market share, and in Europe
this is 30% (increased from almost 27% last year). It will come
as no surprise that Google Play and the Apple App Store are the
two main distributors of mobile apps globally. These numbers
illustrate further what our pumpkin farmer experiences: You
either play the game, follow the rules, and pay the fees
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tweaktown.com/news/81567/apples-30-app-store-commission-is-supracompetitive-court-declares/index.html&quot;&gt;arbitrarily determined by Apple&lt;/a&gt;, or you lose access to your
potential customers. However, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; install a 3rd party
application market on Android phones. One of them, called
&lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/&quot;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;, is one that exclusively distributes free software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the judge in the recent &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/21060631/apple-epic-judgement.pdf&quot;&gt;Epic Games v Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lawsuit in
the United States stated in her nearly 200 page court
opinion, “not every business is entitled to have access to what
is effectively shelf space if they cannot afford to pay a
commission to the platform host.” The positions of Apple or
Google are hard to fight, because both organizations are
extremely powerful and they are financially able to protect this
power. Another reason is that court and governments globally lack
in-house technical expertise, they have to rely on
so-called “experts,” who have immense influence on the
verdict. But most importantly, legislation on issues pertaining
to technology is so far behind that legal conclusions are
difficult to draw, and mostly appealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it so hard to show that Apple is in the wrong here? &lt;em&gt;Epic
Games v Apple&lt;/em&gt; sheds some light on this. To prove Apple was
monopolizing the market, it had to be established first what
market Apple would have this monopoly in. Apple has a hand in
many different markets. To name a few, the mobile phone market,
iOS apps, and the bigger gaming market. In this instance, it was
settled that the market was mobile game payments. In the
aforementioned case in the Netherlands, the focus was reduced to
primarily dating market apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These results &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown&quot;&gt;affect the verdict greatly&lt;/a&gt;, “Epic claimed
Apple had abused a monopoly on the iOS app ecosystem; Apple
claimed Fortnite was playing in the more competitive overall
digital game market.” The conclusion bypasses Apple’s control
over users of mobile phones and the App Store any iOS user is
controlled by, because Apple does not have a monopoly in &lt;em&gt;mobile
gaming&lt;/em&gt;… yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epic Games may have failed to demonstrate conclusively the
monopolist position of Apple when it comes to mobile game
payments, but according to Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers of the
United States District Court for the Northern District of
California, “Apple’s anti-steering provisions hide critical
information from consumers and illegally stifle consumer
choice. When coupled with Apple’s incipient antitrust violations,
these anti-steering provisions are anticompetitive and a
nationwide remedy to eliminate those provisions is warranted.”
This is a small victory for developers who would be allowed to
link to other in-app purchases and could potentially bypass
Apple’s cut. The case of &lt;em&gt;Epic Games v Apple&lt;/em&gt; is interesting
because it shakes the position of Apple, but let’s not forget
that Epic Games itself has no intention for its users to be any
more free than Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing may come of this particular case either, as it will be
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/apple-is-appealing-epic-games-case-anti-steering-2021-10?international=true&amp;amp;r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;&gt;held up in appeals&lt;/a&gt; for the coming years, but countries all
over the world have come to realize that the position Apple has
ascribed itself violates people’s rights, developer or
otherwise. In addition to the new charges from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2021/04/30/tech/apple-eu-antitrust/index.html&quot;&gt;European
Committee&lt;/a&gt;, a parallel initiative to the &lt;em&gt;Epic Games v Apple&lt;/em&gt;
court ruling in the US is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blumenthal.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/8.11.21%20-%20Open%20App%20Markets%20Act%20-%20Bill%20Text.pdf&quot;&gt;Open App Markets Act&lt;/a&gt;, proposed
by Senators Amy Klobuchar, Richard Blumenthal, and Marsha
Blackburn, which would place a variety of restrictions on major
app marketplaces in order to protect competition. On August 31,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/08/south-korea-law-forces-google-and-apple-to-open-up-app-store-payments/&quot;&gt;South Korea passed new regulations&lt;/a&gt; requiring Apple to accept
alternate payments in their respective app stores. Apple has made
other concessions in recent months as well, including
allowing “reader apps,” any app that requires a subscription to
use, to direct users to their own &lt;a href=&quot;https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/09/08/us-lawmakers-moving-forward-with-app-store-bill-despite-apple-changes&quot;&gt;Web sites for
payments&lt;/a&gt;. That specific guideline change came in response to
a probe by Japan’s Fair Trade Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People, developers, and governments around the world are
beginning to rise against Apple’s powerful and restrictive
position. According to a timeline &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/22667242/apple-app-store-major-policy-changes-history&quot;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt; put
together, “Apple has had to change more App Store policies
between August 26, 2021 to September 10, than in any other period
in its history.” Apple is fighting to hold its grip on the App
Store, because it increasingly delivers a large percentage of its
annual profits at &lt;a href=&quot;https://moneyprofitreport.com/epic-games-court-ruling-unlikely-to-seriously-damage-apples-services-business/&quot;&gt;an immense margin&lt;/a&gt;. Apple (and Google)
often cite &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2020/09/25/tech/apple-fortnite-epic-games-lawsuit/index.html&quot;&gt;safety and keeping users secure from malicious
software&lt;/a&gt; as the main reasons why they should have the
unbridled right to control how and which software is distributed
to millions of users, and often also the main reason for imposing
Digital Restrictions Management (DRM), but at a margin estimated
at nearly 72%, you would think that they can afford to protect
users &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; their freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Threatening danger, fraud, or malware, are all clever and often
used ways of scaring users into agreeing to ever more restricting
user terms and conditions. The cost of developing ways to keep
users safe is not about finances, but power. Besides limiting
developers financially, they can also not distribute free
software via Apple. Again, under the guise of “protection,”
Apple’s App Store only allows technologically restricted
software. And make no mistake, despite misleading advertising,
there is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/campaigns/apple&quot;&gt;no freedom for users&lt;/a&gt; in the way Apple runs
its App Store. We must remember that having freedom is
not “insecure,” rather, it is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/bulletin/2019/spring/its-not-just-about-privacy&quot;&gt;precondition for true
privacy&lt;/a&gt;. Without access to source code, we can never verify
privacy, or safety on Apple’s devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every security claim about the benefits of vetting installable
software is actually an argument for a world where the &lt;em&gt;user can
choose which security vetting entity to trust&lt;/em&gt;. This world
requires free software. You can think of this as the monopoly
Apple has – a monopoly on who gets to decide what software is
installable and usable on iOS devices. There are no significant
competitors because Apple threatens them with legal action, and
takes extreme technical measures to stop users from trying them
out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of trying to maintain the status quo one court case after
the other, it is time to evolve, Apple, move forward &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt;
freedom, not against it. As one of the most successful and
richest companies in the world, we can not let it tell us that
absolute control over our user freedom is a justifiable price to
pay to make sure its technology is up to par. Users deserve the
freedom to decide what programs they want to install and run on
their devices. Developers deserve a market place where they can
distribute their work. Apple is trying to hold on to the power
they currently have, but we have to rally &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defectivebydesign.org/apple#email&quot;&gt;for change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we do, Apple will have no choice but to stop trying to hold
users hostage on its platforms. But we also need to keep our eyes
on the goal. Just because some parties are fighting to take power
away from Apple, we cannot sit back and let power transfer from
one proprietary organization to another. Governments need to take
measures and proper legislation needs to be established, not to
assure financial gain for anyone, but for free software
developers to distribute and fund their work, and, and for the
freedom for users to control our own devices, to install and to
run the software we choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoë Kooyman
Program Manager
Free Software Foundation&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zoë Kooyman</name></author><summary type="html">This message is fowarded from the Free Software Foundation’s “Free Software Supporter” mailing list. The original message is as below.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Free Software, Education in China and the COVID-19 Pandemic</title><link href="https://aveniracademia.org/2021/10/20/education.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Free Software, Education in China and the COVID-19 Pandemic" /><published>2021-10-20T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-10-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://aveniracademia.org/2021/10/20/education</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aveniracademia.org/2021/10/20/education.html">&lt;p&gt;I am a secondary school student from Shanghai, China.  This email
discusses the problems I discovered in the Chinese educational system,
in terms of students’ right to freedom in computing and options to
control the COVID-19 pandemic from the standpoint of a person living in
China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When COVID-19 broke out in 2020, students were required to watch lecture
videos produced by the city’s education department for twenty minutes,
then join the Tencent Meetings room to discuss in their own class for
10–15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching the videos wasn’t an issue for me.  Our apartment has cable TV,
where the videos are broadcast; there was also a website that played the
livestream without JavaScript.  However, Tencent Meetings presented a
problem to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I run Arch Linux. (Currently, I run Hyperbola
GNU/Linux-libre, a Free Software-only distribution, which would have
made this even harder.) Tencnet Meetings, claiming to support “all
operating systems and platforms”, only supports Windows and macOS. (I
wonder how they passed the resolution to display that statement, I
believe that they have many programmers who use GNU/Linux.) (As of
October 2021, a classmate noted that there is a “Linux versuon”.) School
required Tencent Meetings, therefore I went through a hard proccess to
setup QEMU running a Windows 7 virtural machine—I believed that 7
would be slightly better than 10 in terms of privacy, though as always
with nonfree software, I can’t really know for sure.  It was slightly
unstable, which is an annoyance, for example the connection from the
Windows audio server to pulseaudio would stop working from time to time,
but it was acceptable.  Though my setup was okay (in the perspective of
my school), it left me in a psycological crisis about education and
freedom. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offline classes resumed in May 2020, as most of China has minimal cases
of COVID-19.  This freed me from using a proprietary
non-privacy-respecting bloated piece of software in a virtual machine,
but it did not free me from teachers’ requirement to use WeChat (think
of it as the equiv of WhatsApp in China), Xiaoheiban (A proprietary
classroom information distribution system), or other pieces of nonfree
software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to the beliefs stated in the GNU Education project, I believe
that schools and educaion are a means of sharing information and
knowledge.  I understand that meeting software and lesson management
software are used as means of distributing knowledge, rather than the
knowledge being distributed themselves.  However, I believe this doesn’t
lead to the argument that the mandate of proprietary software usage is
just, for three reasons as below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are always going to be curious students who wonder how the
trchnology works.  Proprietary software denies them this right.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The usage of proprietary software when young may implant dependence
on it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Education is a right and a responsility.  Mandating nonfree software
in education adds unjust responsibilities on students.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point 1 and 2 are explained well in the Education section of the GNU
website, therefore I am not going to focus on them.  Focusing on the
third point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under laws of almost all countries, citizens have the right to an
education.  Traditionally, this involves going to school, meeting
teachers and classmates, listening to classes, taking notes, passing
exams (I have strong opinions that exam systems ought to change to
better represent individual talents, but this is out of scope of this
memo.) and finishing homework.  Students loose a slight bit of their
time and freedom of movement (as in, it’s not easy to move to a house
100 miles away from school), in exchange for being educated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, with schools requiring the use of nonfree software, in effect
students are required to give up their privacy, and digital freedom,
both crucial rights in modern society, as the effect of needing to use
nonfree software.  The right to education has effectively turned into an
exchange for other basic rights.  This is not acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, in countries like China, 9 years of education is mandatory
for children.  I understand this law as a means to the goal of creating
a knowledgeble and educated society, which is good.  However, when
mandatory edication mandates nonfree software, it deduces to “children
are required to use nonfree software”.  So, being a child here is pretty
unlucky, because there goes your right to privacy, your independence,
and your freedom, because of a law that’s supposed to help society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to stop using nonfree software in education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In th beginning of this email, I mentioned COVID-19.  You might be
wondering how China fully put the pandemic under control in just 5
months, which is seemingly impossible if all you know is how the US
dealt with this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is that China is implementing strict contact tracing.  This
is extremely easy because of the prevaliance of survillance.  Many would
argue that this is a benefit of survillance, which I believe to be true.
However, no comparisons were given between losing privacy and increasing
the risk or infection.  Briefly inspecting this idea in my head, it’s
really hard to think about—privacy and freedom is important in the
long term, at the cost of many lives in the pandemic.  The lives of
these dead are gone—they lose not only privacy and computing freedom,
they lose their lives, which costs them their oppurtunity to persue
their dreams in this world, and they have no freedom of choice, speech,
etc as they aren’t alive.  Once again, this is hard to wrap my mind
around, therefore I would especially like to invite the community to
discuss this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contact tracing system used is not Free Software.  At first I didn’t
understand why (except for the explanation that they want to profit from
harming citizens), but I noticed that the authenticity and accuracy of
the system may be affected if users are allowed to modify their
software.  This seems to be the core of some problems with regards to
software freedom—here, the user is not running software to complete
their tasks.  Rather, it’s the government’s way to maintain public
safety, therefore I believe that whether users should be able to modify
software in these conditions is up to discussion.  Back to the point,
since a green-code proof from the system is needed to get in a lot of
places, a person basically needs to use proprietary software to live a
normal life (to get into coffee shops, for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In America and other countries, things aren’t that good either.  For one,
the pandemic isn’t controlled well.  As a consequence, a lot of places
require negative COVID tests to do stuff.  A thread on the LibrePlanet
mailing list discusses this issue, as a lot of these tests require
nonfree software on users’ phones.  Note that this thread spans several
months long, as it is a hot discussion, so look in the september and
october archives too.  The thread explains the implications clearly, thus
I am not discussing it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/libreplanet-discuss/2021-08/msg00008.html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I heard that some US courts require ZOOM for online cases,
therefore it seems that a person’ right to judicial justice comes at the
cost of digital freedom.  I can’t confirm this, but if that’s true, I’m
truely disappointed at the judicial system, even though I’m not a US
citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking foward to a freer society, or at least one where the above
problems get solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,
Andrew Yu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verbatim redistribution of this memo is allowed worldwide, but
changing it is not allowed, as this is not a technical memo, rather,
a politicol-philosophical opinion paper.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Yu</name></author><summary type="html">I am a secondary school student from Shanghai, China. This email discusses the problems I discovered in the Chinese educational system, in terms of students’ right to freedom in computing and options to control the COVID-19 pandemic from the standpoint of a person living in China.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Free Software?</title><link href="https://aveniracademia.org/whatisfreesoftware/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Free Software?" /><published>2021-10-20T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-10-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://aveniracademia.org/free-software</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aveniracademia.org/whatisfreesoftware/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-libre-software&quot;&gt;What is libre software?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Free software” means software that respects users’ freedom and community. Roughly, it means that the users have the freedom to run, copy, distribute, study, change and improve the software. Thus, “free software” is a matter of liberty, not price. To understand the concept, you should think of “free” as in “free speech,” not as in “free beer”. We sometimes call it “libre software,” borrowing the French or Spanish word for “free” as in freedom, to show we do not mean the software is gratis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You may have paid money to get copies of a free program, or you may have obtained copies at no charge. But regardless of how you got your copies, you always have the freedom to copy and change the software, even to sell copies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libre software is software that respects the freedom of its users. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://fsf.org&quot;&gt;Free Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; calls it “Free Software”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard people referring to it as “Open Source Software”. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/open-source-misses-the-point.en.html&quot;&gt;“Why Open Source Misses the Point of Free Software”&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://stallman.org&quot;&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/a&gt; at the GNU project, the term “Open Source” does not explain it correctly. However, he notes that the term “Libre Software” is aligned with “Free Software”, though “Libre” is not plain English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-better-than-proprietary-software-alternatively-what-is-wrong-with-proprietary-software-that-isnt-true-with-libre-software&quot;&gt;Why is better than proprietary software? (Alternatively, what is wrong with proprietary software that isn’t true with libre software?)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think that since nonfree software is so popular, there is a good reason to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some sense, that is (sadly) true. People use proprietary operating systems like Windows, because they are compatible with the software that came first—proprietary software. This is partly due to the prominence of proprietary software developers rising since the 1980s. The Free Software Movement started later, and we need to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people, which may or may not include you, almost exclusively use proprietary software. Microsoft Windows, macOS, Microsoft Office, etc. You name it. These pieces of software are not libre software—they do not give you any permission to read, edit, or use their code in any way, shape or form. This results in the user—even those with exceptional programming abilities—unable to clearly know what is going on in the program they are using. What if the program is selling their users’ data? What if they are attempting to use that data to manipulate the users’ minds? We have no way of knowing, since even a programmer couldn’t figure it out without access to the source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, libre software allows anybody to view the source code. With minimum programming knowledge, they could easily know what is going on in the program. They could also add features to it, be it developed by themself or by others who are willing to share their code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives users absolute control over their computing, a.k.a. freedom, along with much more privacy. You don’t have to worry about being manipulated by someone who is willing to sell your information to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;then-how-do-i-get-started&quot;&gt;Then how do I get started?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are currently using Windows, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/working-together/moving/windows&quot;&gt;The FSF’s guide for Windows users to switch to free software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are currently using macOS, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/working-together/moving/mac-os-x&quot;&gt;The FSF’s guide for macOS users to switch to free software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;where-can-i-learn-more&quot;&gt;Where can I learn more?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://audio-video.gnu.org/video/rms-2020-12-04-waterloo-why-operating-systems-and-other-software-should-be-free.webm&quot;&gt;Richard Stallman’s Talk on Free Operating Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subscribe to this website using ways described on &lt;a href=&quot;https://aveniracademia.org/about/&quot;&gt;the About page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Yu</name></author><summary type="html">What is libre software? “Free software” means software that respects users’ freedom and community. Roughly, it means that the users have the freedom to run, copy, distribute, study, change and improve the software. Thus, “free software” is a matter of liberty, not price. To understand the concept, you should think of “free” as in “free speech,” not as in “free beer”. We sometimes call it “libre software,” borrowing the French or Spanish word for “free” as in freedom, to show we do not mean the software is gratis. You may have paid money to get copies of a free program, or you may have obtained copies at no charge. But regardless of how you got your copies, you always have the freedom to copy and change the software, even to sell copies.</summary></entry></feed>